Guide to the Robert Grenier Papers
Department of Special Collections
- Series III. Others' Manuscripts 1950 - 1999, Alphabetized by author, dated/ chronologized and counted (by pages of text) in folders. Contained in 3½ boxes.
  - A. Manuscripts of Original Work Sent RG for Review and Comment
    - 11. LARRY EIGNER Materials, (ca. 165 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - Materials relating to "Larry Eigner Remembered: A Tribute to Larry Eigner (1927-1996) & His Work" at UC Berkeley, April 10, 1996 & Buffet Supper, April 11, 1996 at Beverly & Richard Eigner's home
    - 12. CURTIS FAVILLE Materials, (ca. 88 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - CF ts. letter to RG, 1970 Mar 17, enclosing
      - CF ts. of collection of CF poems, PEANUTBUTTER, (xerox)
    - 13. KATHLEEN FRASER Materials, (13 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - KF print-out of KF poem "Firestorm" dated 1993 November
      - KF holograph letter to RG, 1995 Feb 7, enclosing
      - KF print-out of KF poem sequence "WING"
        (Pub. in Conjunctions, Spring 1995)
    - 14. BENJAMIN FRIEDLANDER Materials, (43 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - BF ts. of BF poem "HEARD AFTER READING A PHANTOM ANTHEM" ("'86/'87")
      - BF holograph postcard to RG etc., 1997 Sept 21
      - BF ts. note on Red Shift by P. Inman (Roof, 1988), (xerox)
      - BF holograph letter to RG
        re Leslie Scalapino's introduction to RG's WHAT I BELIEVE TRANSPIRATION / TRANSPIRING MINNESOTA (0 Books, 1991)
      - BF/Peter Culley visual work announcing joint reading 1991 Nov 13
      - BF ts. of BF poem "HOME FROM WORK / AFTER THE WAR" ("for Bob") (1992?)
      - BF print-out of BF literary biography of Larry Eigner (1994?)
        Pub. by (Gale Research?)
      - BF Obituary for Larry Eigner
        Pub. in The Poetry Project Newsletter, No. 161 (1996 Apr - 1996 May)
    - 15. DARRELL GRAY Materials, (10 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - DG original ts. & holograph poems found by RG in kitchen at 2338 McGee in (1980?), returning home:
        - "AN OFFERING", (DG ts.),signed
        - "AFTER THE NATIVES NOD OUT", (DG ts.)
        - "ICE BOX", (DG ts.) ("for Bob" in holograph)
        - "THE OLDEST PROBLEM", (DG ts.)
        - "YOU NEED A CUP", (DG holograph)
        - "KIT'S PEN", (DG holograph, initialed)
        - "percolations", (DG holograph)
        - "While The Chicken Cooks", (DG holograph, initialed)
    - 16. AMY ELIZA GRENIER Materials, (84 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - Fourteen AG drawings & watercolors, 1970 - 1976
        (1st being purple creature, on cover of this 1 (1971))
      - Two AG holograph poems ("bills" & "food"), ca. 1974
      - Four photomat snapshots of AG & RG, ca. 1970
      - Three photos of AG at Franconia College, 1973 - 1974
      - Two AG cover designs for possible use re RG's book of poems SERIES (This Press, 1978)
      - AG copy of A PICTURE FOR HAROLD'S ROOM
        story & pictures by Crockett Johnson (Scholastic Book Services, 1973)
    - 17. JUDSON A. GRENIER, JR. Materials, (82. pp. total) (Box 009)
      - JG ts. poem "to Mother/January 23, 1950", (xerox)
      - PRAIRIE WINDS AND SEA WINDS, poems by JG & DBawings by Nancy (Hicks) Grenier, signed
        (authors' edition, Manhattan Beach, CA, 1958)
      - JG ts. of "THE AMERICANIZATION OF LOS ANGELES", 1985 June 28, (xerox)
        A paper prepared for presentation at the Annual Conference of the Pacific Coast Branch, American Historical Association, Stanford University, 1985 June 28.
    - 18. LYN HEJINIAN Materials, (91 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - LH tss. of LH poems/drafts from early 1980's, (xeroxes):
        - "THE PIT" 1982 Jan 15
        - "RESISTANCE" 1982 June 10
        - "PROSE" 1982 Aug
        - "EXIT" 1982 Oct 28
        - "Worlds on words..." 1982 Nov 5
        - "PARADISE" 1983 Jan 14
        - "THE GUARD" n.d., (two versions)
        - "VIDE" n.d.
      - LH ts. of essay "Language and 'Paradise'" on Gertrude Stein (1983?), (xerox)
      - LH ts. of LH's My Life updated/1987 version, (xerox)
        Pub. by Sun & Moon Press (1987), inscribed to RG & KF
      - RG holograph letter to LH, 1988 May 26, (xerox)
        re My Life & LH work generally
    - 19. ANSELM HOLLO Materials, (ca. 159 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - AH ts. of AH book "PICK UP THE HOUSE/New & Selected Poems" (1985), (xerox)
        Inscribed "THANKS/&/GIVING,/at McGee Manor--/Big Love, to All In There:/Anselm 1 Dec 85", pub. by Coffee House Press (1987)
      - AH print-out of AH report "Nobel Laureate in Salt Lake City: A Cultural Evening in the City of the Latter-Day Saints", 1987 Nov 18
      - AH print-out letter to RG, 1989 Jan 19, enclosing
      - AH print-out of AH poem sequence "MINIGOLF" (1989)
      - "Anselm Hollo" from Contemporary Authors Autobiography Series, Vol. 19 (Gale Research, 1993), (xerox)
      - AH holograph letter to RG, 1997 Nov 4, enclosing
      - AH print-out of AH poem sequence "16 brief epics for bob grenier" w/ AH inscription
    - 20. FANNY HOWE Materials, (ca. 165 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - Two FH poems, "QUIET ONES" & "OUR HEAVEN'S WORDS" copied by Joanne Kyger to notice reading by FH at Bolinas Library, 1991 Feb 15
      - "ON QUIETISM", Catholic tract provided RG by FH for informational purposes (1991?)
      - FH course materials for her "Mystical Writing", UC/San Diego, Spring 1992
      - FH ts. of draft collection of poems, ANNAGHMAKERRIG (1993?), (xerox)
        Many of which later occur in O'CLOCK (Reality Street Editions, 1995)
      - FH holograph letter to RG, 1995 May 1, enclosing
      - FH print-out of ms. of O'CLOCK (Reality Street, 1995)
    - 21. P. INMAN Materials, (18 pp. total) (Box 009)
      - Pl ts. of OCKER, a series for Robert Grenier
        Pub. by Tuumba Press (1982)
    - 22. KENNETH IRBY Materials, (ca. 614 pp. total, so far) (Box 011)
      - KI poem "WAITING FOR THE PHONE TO BE PUT IN" for RG, 23 OCT 62, (KI ts.)
      - KI poem "THE ANNIVERSARY", 9 DEC 62, (KI ts.)
      - KI poem "EXILE SCENES" for RG, 19 FEB 63, (KI ts. inscribed for RG, w/ KI ts. letter)
      - KI poem "THE OPENING" for Lisa & Paco, 22 FEB (63?), (KI ts.)
      - KI poem "for Bob & Emily" (1963?), (KI ts.)
      - KI marriage poem "for Bob & Emily Grenier", May 26, 1963, (KI ts.)
      - KI poem "Poem beginning w/ a line from Duncan", 24 JUL-28 AUG 63, (KI holograph)
      - KI poem beginning "The roadrunner that crossed my yard...", 17-19 SEP 63, (KI ts. w/ holograph notes)
      - KI poem beginning w/ a line from Blake, "The stars are threshed, and the souls are threshed from their husks", 26 OCT 63, (KI ts.)
      - KI poem beginning "There is snow reported this morning on the radio...", 31 OCT 63, (KI ts.)
      - KI poem "for William Frederick Kimball, b. 15 APR 64", 26-29 APR 64, (copy of KI ts. w/ KI holograph notes)
      - KI poem beginning "April has gotten warm finally...", 25 APR 64, (KI ts.)
      - KI broadside "THE OREGON TRAIL", 17 JAN 63
        Pub. by bp eight: dialogue press, lawrence, kansas, inscribed to RG (Oct. 64)
      - Robert Duncan poem "MELVILLE AFTER PIERRE", 1957
        Sent RG by KI from Wild Dog 19/20 (Dec 1965)
      - KI review of Robert Duncan's ROOTS AND BRANCHES (1st draft Apr 1966), (xerox of KI ts.)
        Discovered & sent to RG by KI accompanied by KI holograph letter, 28 Jan 96
      - Folder of KI ts. poems & notes from 1968-1969:, (xeroxes)
        (many of these pub. in RELATION (Black Sparrow, 1970) & CATALPA (Tansy Press, 1977))
        - "PREFACE", Feb-Mar 69
        - "SOME ETYMOLOGICAL NOTES"
        - "fragments", 31 Aug-17 Sep 69
        - "(recent fragments)", 2-3 Jun 69
        - "STRAWBERRY CANYON POEM", 22 Aug 68
        - "PT REYES POEM-2", 7 Jul 68
        - "SOME ECOLOGICAL NOTES", 17-20 Jun 69
        - "SEXUAL SOLITUDES", 28 Apr-30 Jul 69
        - "for John Thorpe", 23 Jul 69
      - KI New Year's greeting, Dec 69, (KI holograph)
        KI trans. of Pasternak poem "AFTER THE STORM"
      - KI New Year's greeting, Dec 70 KI trans. of Mandelstam poem beginning "How the feminine silver burns...", (KI holograph)
        w/note to Bob & Emily
      - KI xerox of pages from 0. Mandelstam, Selected Poems, trans. Brown & Merwin (Oxford, 1973), w/ arrow toward #113 beginning "I have forgotten the word I wanted to say..."
      - KI poem beginning "the arc of high school ache...", JAN-FEB 75, (KI ts.)
      - KI ts. letter to RG, 29 Nov 77
        Enclosing xerox of KI's "SOME NOTES ON GERRIT LANSING'S THE HEAVENLY TREE GROWS DOWNWARD" (KI ts.), pub. in CREDENCES, Vol. 2, Nos. 3-4 (March 1978)
      - Xerox of p. 20 of KI's CATALPA (Tansy Press, 1977)
        w/ poem beginning "The bell of a train passing...", w/ KI holograph addition
      - KI poem beginning "late in Winter when thaws beginning Spring...", 1 MAR 78
        Inscribed for RG (KI ts.), pub. in CALL STEPS (Station Hill/Tansy, 1992)
      - KI broadside, two poems beginning "restless the rain returns...", 20 SEP 78 &"no animal system lately...", 11 DEC 78 (Tansy, 1980)
        Inscribed for RG & KF, both later pub. in CALL STEPS (Station Hill/Tansy, 1992)
      - KI "MS. OF A BOOK OF POEMS 1977-1979
        AS YET UNTITLED" (Later/pub. as CALL STEPS Station Hill/Tansy, 1992), dated November 1981 & inscribed for Bob & Kathleen, 1 DEC 81 (xerox of KI ts.)
      - KI xerox of page from John Julius Norwich, CHRISTMAS CRACKERS (Allen Lane, 1981)
      - KI collection of travel notations "RIDING THE DOG", JAN 77-OCT 81, dated JAN 82 & inscribed "a garland of transcontinental sashay on the great gray pup & the ways of Trail/for Bob & Kathleen/5 JAN 82", (xerox of KI ts.)
        (different version pub. as The Zelot, No. 4 (January 1982))
      - KI prose poem beginning "midwinter days when the focus stays inside entirely...", 14 JAN 82
        Inscribed for Bob & Kathleen (xerox of KI ts.)
      - KI holograph letter to RG, 8 SEP 82
        Enclosing xerox of KI ts. of "ARCHIPELAGO/part one of the ms. of a book of poems 1974-1976 as yet untitled", inscribed to RG (KI notes "revised in a few places from the Tuumba version (ARCHIPELAGO, Tuumba Press, 1976), & some additions, too")
      - KI xerox of Gerrit Lansing note "La P(l)age Poetique" by GL, dated June 19, 1983
      - Brochure & schedule for conference at UC Davis, "THE WRITINGS AND THE WORLD OF MARY BUTTS" Feb. 23-24,1984
        & xerox of KI ts. of KI's edition of MARY BUTTS POEMS /TYPESCRIPTS FROM NOTEBOOKS (unpublished as of 3/1/99)
      - KI prose poem "(exercitatio/praecipere)", 13-19 SEP 84, (xerox of KI ts.)
        Inscribed for RG, DEC 1984
      - KI holograph letter to RG, 25 FEB 85
        Enclosing xerox of KI ts. of KI review/article "ROBERT DUNCAN. Ground Work: Before the War", inscribed for RG
      - KI xerox of version of KI's "ROBERT DUNCAN. Ground Work: Before the War" in CONJUNCTIONS 7 (1985)
      - KI ms. of collection of poems, "DENMARK / Poems 1973-1974", (xerox of KI ts.)
        Inscribed for RG, August 1985
      - KI poem beginning "(After a gift of poems, written while travelling in China, from Roy Gridley...", 28-29 JUL 86, (xerox of KI ts.)
        Inscribed for Bob & Kathleen
      - KI poem beginning "now into the undersight...", 1986 Sep 13-14, (xerox of KI ts.)
      - KI poem beginning "rough double cups awhirl...", 22 JUL 86, (KI ts. xerox)
        Inscribed for Bob & Kathleen SEP 86
      - KI poem beginning "that is the tree matrix...", 19 OCT 86, (xerox of KI ts.)
        Inscribed for Bob & Kathleen, "to go w/ those of 22 JUL & 13-14 SEP 86"
      - KI ts. letter to RG, 18 MAY 88
        Enclosing KI holograph worksheet & xerox of KI ts. draft of review, "Robert Duncan. Ground Work II: In the Dark"
      - KI xerox of pp. 277-288 from CONJUNCTIONS 12 (1988)
        Containing Robert Creeley's "Wisdom as Such: In Respect of Robert Duncan" & KI's pub. version of review, "ROBERT DUNCAN. Ground Work II: In the Dark"
      - RG piece "QUESTIONS FOR UNCLE KEN / August 17/89", (xerox of RG holograph, 8 pp.)
      - KI broadside, "(two studies)", with poems beginning "of curly beechbark oak..." (1981) & "the noon pass brings rain..." (1989) (Tansy Press, 1989)
        Inscribed for RG SEP 89
      - Essay on KI's work, 'RACE OF READINESS BEFORE 0' ERTAKEN': THE ALLEGORICAL AND PASTORAL ART OF KENNETH IRBY" by Ed Schelb, ca. 1989, (xerox of ES ts. w/ holograph annotations by RG)
      - Bolinas Hearsay News, June 18, 1990
        w/ KI poem beginning "The students from Cracow leave..." & "POINT REYES POEM, 2", w/ notice of KI reading at Bolinas Library, June 21, 1990
      - KI selection of poems for :that: magazine (No. 19):
        - "The flecks of other colors...", 27 FEB 92
        - "Moroni on the play...", 24 JAN 93
        - "The antiphonal protagonists take pause...", 4 FEB 93
        - "(homage to Richard Lovelace)", 14 NOV 93
        - "But the cocklight is of the light above..." 11 DEC 93
        - "I have a chair in the stair well...", 4 DEC 93
        - "(final exam)", 14 DEC 93, (xerox of KI tss., w/ KI pencil dates)
      - KI selection of poems for First Intensity mag. (No. 2):
        - "Evangel of the Morning...", 18 AUG 92
        - "(to almost midnight New Year's Eve in Glasgow", 31 DEC 92
        - "that after all to walk into a restaurant...", 31 JAN 93
        - "(homage to Anna Akhmatova)", 16 FEB 93, (xerox of KI tss., w/ KI pencil dates)
      - KI xerox of David Rattray obit from N.Y. Times, March 25, 1993
        w/ xerox of DR poem, "Mr. Peacock"
      - KI ts. of KI article, "(Some notes on Zukofsky's 80 Flowers and Michele J. Leggott's Reading Zukofsky's "80 Flowers" (Johns Hopkins U. Press, 1989))"
        (xerox), inscribed for RG, August 1993 (pub. in Sulfur magazine)
      - KI selection of poems for "the final Notus" magazine:
        - "Mimosa, sensitive, the mime..."
        - "The station is the sphincter of arousal..."
        - "So my mother has poured ice water..."
        - "healing machines"
        - "The parable and trump..." (called "SEPTEMBER SET"), (xerox of KI tss., w/ KI pencil date 4-19 SEP 93)
      - KI introduction to Denis O'Mahony's Black Pig (author's ed., 1994)
        (xerox of KI ts.), inscribed for RG, FEB 1994
      - KI selection of poems, sent/inscribed for RG, NOV 1994:
        - "To have a guest...", 24 JUL 94
        - "The boys are sitting on the front steps...", 5 AUG 94
        - "Would you take the diaphany of ivory...", 10 AUG 94
        - "'Would that I might be rubbed away...'", 23 AUG 94
        - "There is the bare and rich delight...", 1994 Aug 25 - 1994 Sep 1
        - "On a winejug tree...", 22 SEP 94
        - "The down of stone...", 13 OCT 94, (xerox of KI tss., w/ KI pencil dates)
      - KI poem "(Homage to Kandinsky and Hartley)", 29 AUG - 24 SEP 95, (xerox of KI ts.)
        Inscribed for RG, FEB 1997
      - KI poem "(Visitations)", 1995 Oct 22 - 1995 Nov 5, (xerox of KI ts.)
      - KI course materials for English 332 at U. of Kansas:
        - "SOME STUDY TOPICS/QUESTIONS ON TROILUS & CRESSIDA", 8 MAR 96
        - "SOME STUDY QUESTIONS & TOPICS ON OTHELLO", 15 MAR 96
        - "SOME STUDY QUESTIONS & TOPICS ON ANTONY & CLEOPATRA", 12 APR 96
        - "SOME STUDY QUESTIONS & TOPICS ON THE WINTER'S TALE", 19 APR 96, (xerox of KI tss., w/ KI pencil notations)
      - Three KI poems sent/inscribed for RG, January 1998:
        - "The king's seal and the king's reef...", 21 SEP - 23 OCT 97
        - "(Instructions)", 25 SEP 97
        - "(Borrowers)", 5 OCT 97, (xerox of KI tss., w/ KI pencil dates)
      - KI ts. letter to RG ,13 JAN 98enclosing:
        - Commentary on Rilke's "ELEGY ONE" by Peter & Sheila Stern
          (xeroxed from RILKE'S DUINO ELEGIES: CAMBRIDGE READINGS (Duckworth & Ariadne Press, 1996))
      - Two KI poems sent RG in: January 1998
        - "The quiet intricate interior forest...", 15 JAN 98
        - "(at Ruben Dario's birthday)", 18 JAN 98, (xerox of KI tss., w/ KI holograph dates)
      - KI poem (draft) sent RG in March 1999, "(tulip etudes)", dated March 1999, (xerox of KI ts.)
        Inscribed "for Bob - to Greet Spring!"
    - 23. ALASTAIR JOHNSTON Materials, (ca. 394 pp. total) (Box 010)
      - AJ tss. of two drafts of AJ collection of poems, HORROR VACUUI, from the early 1980's, (xerox)
      - AJ ts. of WAZEE HUKUMBUKU, AJ African adventures, stories, etc., July-November 1983, (xerox)
      - Issue of Fine Print, Vol. 11, No. 3 (July 1985)
        w/ notice of large broadside poem "Through the Manacle" by RG, illustrated in letterpress & pochoir by Frances Butler, pub. by Poltroon Press in 1985, w/ photo of broadside work (see broadside in XII.L. below)
      - AJ's A Bibliography of The White Rabbit Press (Poltroon/Anacapa, 1985), (xerox)
      - AJ ts. of AJ's THE LITERATURE OF NINETEENTH CENTURY TYPEFOUNDERS' SPECIMENS (1st draft, 1986), (xerox)
    - 24. JOANNE KYGER Materials, (ca. 64 pp. total) (Box 010)
      - JK/Lee Harwood issue of BEZOAR, Vol. 17, No. 4 (Fall 1979)w/ JK 'novel' THIS OTHER THING
      - JK calligraphic poem, "Here Before Began" given to RG, signed by JK on reverse & dated February 4, 1990
      - Tom Clark review of JK's Just Space (Black Sparrow, 1991), "Essential Observations", (xerox)
        Pub. in San Francisco Chronicle (1991)
      - Bolinas Hearsay News reprint of Tom Clark review of JK's Just Space (November 18, 1991)
      - "Joanne Kyger" from Contemporary Authors Autobiography Series, Vol. 16 (Gale Research, 1992)
      - Materials for JK's Journal Class in Bolinas, April 21, 1993
      - Poster for concert, Genghis Blues at Bolinas Community Center, October 13, 1995 (?)
      - RG color holograph xerox image of two poems, "JOANNE'S PORCH" & "CALTOPIA" from ca. 1995
      - JK ts. of JK poem "View North" for Larry Eigner (dying), February 2, 1996, (xerox)
      - Notes from Bolinas poetry reading group, December 21, 1996 (winter solstice)
      - JK ts. of JK poem/note on Alice Eastwood, "For Bob Grenier out chasing rainbows in Cataract Gulch" from ca. March 1997, (xerox)
        Signed by JK w/ Donald Guravich original holograph drawing
      - JK/Donald Guravich calligraphic poem "Quail Duration" (undated, 1990's)
    - 25. MARCIA LAWTHER Materials, (37 pp. total) (Box 010)
      - ML ts. of long poem, "The Dream of Ursula" from ca. 1987, (xerox)
        w/ ML holographic corrections
    - 26. RICK LONDON Materials, (52 pp. total) (Box 010)
      - RL holograph letter to RG, 9/6/85 enclosing
      - RL chapbook DREAMING CLOSE BY (author's ed., 1985)
      - RL ts. of collection of poems, THE MOTION IS A FALL, (xerox)
    - 27. JIM McCRARY Materials, (68 pp. total) (Box 010)
      - JM print-out letter to RG, November 26, 1991
        Requesting back-cover note for JM book of poems, WEST OF MASS (enclosed)
      - RG ts. of RG back-cover note for WEST OF MASS, (xerox)
      - JM print-out of JM ms. of WEST OF MASS, pub. by Tansy Press (1992)
    - 28. DUNCAN McNAUGHTON Materials, (ca. 167 pp. total) (Box 010)
      - DM ts. of collection of poems, LOVE FOR SALE, dated August 1984 & August 1985, (xerox)
      - DM ts. of collection of poems, LA ROSITA, dated September 1984 - December 1985, (xerox)
      - DM holograph letter to RG, February 2, 1987
        Enclosing xeroxes of passages relating to Egyptian "Ka" from Henri Frankfort's Kingship & the Gods & Budge trans. of The Book of the Dead
      - DM ts. of DM poem, "Sumptuous rain-laden clouds", dated November 18, 1994
    - 29. LAURA MORIARTY Materials, (18 pp. total) (Box 010)
      - LM holograph letter to RG, March 20, 1984, enclosing
      - LM tss. of various LM poems (xeroxes), including
        - "like roads"
        - "8 barriers"
        - 2 pp. sequence beginning "Many held nothing..."
        - "shrines breaking down"
    - 30. DAVE MORICE Materials, (49 pp. total) (Box 010)
      - TILT, a collection of poems & stories by DM (Toothpaste Press, 1971)
    - 31. BOB PERELMAN Materials, (86 pp. total) (Box 010)
      - BP tss. of various BP poems from ca. 1973, (xeroxes)
        One, "Atlantis", pub. in this 5 (winter 1974)
      - BP tss. of various BP works from ca. 1973, (xeroxes)
        BP address, "60 Kinnaird St.", indicates Cambridge, MA period (early 1970's), one, "Sentences", pub. in this 5 (winter 1974)
      - BP tss. of four BP poems:, (xeroxes)
        - "CUPID & PSYCHE"
        - "VIENNA"
        - "AN ESSAY ON STYLE"
        - poem beginning "The doorway's set up..."
          (1st 3 of these works were published in BP's 7 WORKS (The Figures, 1978))
    - 32. JED RASULA Materials, (62 pp. total) (Box 010)
      - JR ts. of JR essay, "ON KEN IRBY", (xerox)
        Pub. in CREDENCES 7 (February 1979)
      - JR ts. of JR essay, "NIETZSCHE IN THE NURSERY" from ca. 1980, (xerox)
      - JR print-out letter to RG, June 15, 1995, enclosing
      - JR print-out of JR essay, "Taking Out the Tracks: Robin Blaser's Syncopation", dated 1995
    - 33. STEPHEN RATCLIFFE Materials, (ca. 185 pp. total) (Box 010)
      - SR ts. of SR book of poems, ROCKS, dedicated to RG, (xerox)
        (draft of Spring-Summer 1993)
      - SR print-out of series of poems called CONVERSATION of draft of Fall 1994
        (SR DBaft, not final version)
      - SR print-outs of two essays included in SR's LISTENING TO READING, SUNY/Albany Press (2000)
        - "Listening to Reading"
        - "Eigner' s Scores"
    - 34. PAT REED Materials, (83 pp. total) (Box 010)
      - PR ts. of collection of PR poems, KISMET, (xerox)
        Pub. by 0 Books (1990) w/ RG marginal notations
      - RG ts. of RG back-cover note for PR's KISMET (0 Books, 1990)
      - PR holograph letter to RG, enclosing PR chapbook of poems, TANGLE BLUE (author's edition, winter solstice, 1993)
    - 35. KIT ROBINSON Materials, (ca. 227 pp. total) (Box 010)
      - KR ts. of KR biographical essay on Anselm Hollo from ca. 1980
      - KR tss. of various KR poems from ca. 1982, (xeroxes)
        Some pub. in KR's RIDDLE ROAD (Tuumba Press, 1982):
        - "ON THE CORNER"
        - "A DAY OFF"
        - "IN THE ORPHEUM BUILDING"
        - "ALL HOTELS"
        - "RIDDLE ROAD"
        - "WITHOUT A COAT"
        - "LEAVENWORTH STREET"
        - "THE VANISHING PROBLEM"
      - KR print-out of KR essay, "What Do You Know: a Read on Larry Eigner" from ca. 1987
      - KR print-out of series of KR poems called "COVERS for Bob"
        Some pub. in KR's COVERS (The Figures, 1988)
      - KR holograph letter to RG, October 19, 1991
        Enclosing xerox of KR ts. of KR essay "The Gaiety of Language and the American Sublime" re Wallace Stevens' writing (from May 1986)
      - KR Interview w/ Rae Armantrout & Laura Moriarty (in American Poetry Archive News)October 8, 1992
      - KR print-out of KR's book of poems, THE CHAMPAGNE OF CONCRETE
        Pub. by Potes & Poets Press (1991)
      - A folder containing KR print-outs of various KR poems, many later collected in KR's DEMOCRACY BOULEVARD (Roof Books, 1998):
        - "Ice Cubes" Ca. 1985
        - "TRANSMISSION"
        - "ORIENTATION"
        - "SENSATION"
        - "TRAJECTORY"
        - "DISTRIBUTION"
        - "PROGRESSION"
        - "SWEETNESS"
        - "COMMISSION"
        - "LEVELING"
        - "IN BETWEENESS"
        - "EQUANIMITY"
        - "ELEGAIC INTERVALS"
        - "PLEASANTON USA"
        - "THE MESSIANIC TREES"
    - 36. LESLIE SCALAPINO Materials, (ca. 994 pp. total) (Box 011)
      - LS ts. of LS essay "Pattern--as Qualitative Infinity", ca. 1986 (?), (xerox)
      - LS ts. of LS draft of WAY, (xerox)
        Pub. by North Point Press (1988)
      - LS ts. of LS draft of ROLL, ca. 1988, (xerox)
      - LS ts. of LS draft of novel THE RETURN OF PAINTING from ca. 1988, (xerox)
        Pub. by North Point Press (1991)
      - LS ts. of LS draft of THE PEARL from ca. 1990, (xerox)
      - LS ts. of LS draft of ORION from ca. February 1990, (xerox)
        Pub. by North Point Press (1991), w/ LS ts. letter to RG, February 19, 1990